<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 08:33:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 building blocks for improving lead retention</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 14:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20933</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Whether you’ve just finished running a successful marketing campaign or have just come back from a successful event, chances are, you now have new leads for your shop. What’s next? Do you email them? What do you say? Today we’ll help you figure just what to do with them to improve your lead retention. 1. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/">5 building blocks for improving lead retention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whether you’ve just finished running a successful marketing campaign or have just come back from a successful event, chances are, you now have new leads for your shop. What’s next? Do you email them? What do you say? Today we’ll help you figure just what to do with them to improve your lead retention.<br />
<span id="more-20933"></span></p>
<h2>1. Qualify Leads</h2>
<p>The first step following lead acquisition is to qualify your leads. Where you did you acquire them from? Where are they currently in the purchase funnel? Three sample categories include: don&#8217;t know the brand, love the brand but haven&#8217;t purchased, new customer. By categorizing your leads, you’ll be able to craft a marketing message that is not only more relevant, but also engaging. </p>
<p>If customers just learned about your brand, they probably aren&#8217;t interested in all the updates you’ve made to an older version of your product. They don’t even know what your product was like before! Misaligned emails can also befuddle your existing customers. For example, sending an old customer a new campaign about your company might lead them to believe you’re changing your company. It’s why we highlight the importance of knowing exactly who you are talking to, so you can maximize the impact of the messages you send. </p>
<h2>2. Activation / Reactivation Campaign</h2>
<p>If you’re targeting those who don’t know your brand, your first step should be introducing them to what you sell. By aligning your message with the right audience, you increase the chances of retaining your customer longer. These activation campaigns aim to get customers interested in your brand and hopefully even engage your company. </p>
<p>If you’re leads are already customers, your goal is to get them to convert again, preferably in the form of a new purchase. If they purchased from you before, give them an incentive to make a purchase. As an added bonus for you, try to get feedback from customers by asking them to complete a survey. Once they provide feedback, they’ll be rewarded with a coupon to shop your site. </p>
<h2>3. Engagement Campaign</h2>
<p>Sometimes customers just aren’t ready to convert. Don&#8217;t discount these leads! Just because they haven’t made a purchase, it doesn’t mean they’re not interested in your business. Keep in touch with your customers by sending regular updates about your products or the latest trends in your industry. This is especially important during low sales seasons when other companies may not be engaging your customers.</p>
<p>Selling pet supplies? Touch base with pet lovers on days like National Dog Day or during <a href="http://www.dogtipper.com/fun/pet-holidays" target="_blank">related events</a> like <a href="http://www.crufts.org.uk/" target="_blank">Crufts</a>. It’s time to get creative to engage customers. There is no wrong or right approach, it’s all about building a relationship with your customers. </p>
<h2>4. Convert <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/" style="font-family: 'Roboto Condensed', Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size:28px;font-weight: 300">Complaints</a> into Hot Leads</h2>
<p>Hearing from customers is always a good thing, even in the form of angry <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-must-follow-rules-for-addressing-your-online-stores-customer-complaints/">customers complaining</a>. Every interaction or touch point of your brand is an opportunity to make a positive impact on your customers. If you can win them over when they are most upset with you, keeping them around will be a piece of cake. </p>
<p>First, listen carefully to customer concerns. They’re taking time to tell you about their problem, so give the courtesy of hearing them out. Stay objective by focusing on the facts and not on emotions. Next, try to find a resolution that works for both you and the customer. Try to deliver the solution in a timely fashion. For some examples and more tips on handling customer complaints, check out these ideas for <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/">how to respond to customer feedback</a>.</p>
<h2>5. Run personalized campaigns</h2>
<p>If you don’t have a new batch of hot leads, there’s still something you can do to re-engage your audience. Most merchants only target customers during major holidays sales, as the majority of people tend to shop at this time. However, there’s a way to keep customers engaged throughout the year, specifically, one special day of the year for each of your customer &#8211; their birthday!</p>
<p>Birthdays are spread throughout the year, so you can kick off this campaign at anytime. Birthdays are about the customer, not you &#8211; so tailor your messages with that in mind. Try messages built on the idea of a birthday gift. Whether you offer a special discount code (like “MYBIRTHDAY” or a birthday gift card, this gesture (although generic) has the ability to feel very personal. </p>
<h2>It’s your turn</h2>
<p>Use one or all of our building blocks to turn your leads from cold to hot and keep them coming back:</p>
<ol>
<li>Qualify your leads</li>
<li>Try activation or reactivation campaigns</li>
<li>Engage customers</li>
<li>Convert complaints into hot leads</li>
<li>Run personalized campaigns</li>
</ol>
<p>Already a lead retention pro? Tell us your secrets in the comments below. Just getting started with PrestaShop? Launch your store today. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/">5 building blocks for improving lead retention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last-minute tips to boost holiday sales</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-boost-holiday-sales/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-boost-holiday-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 13:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20920</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The holiday season is upon us. You’ve decked out your homepage, planned your holiday promotions and set up a targeted communication plan to draw a maximum number of shoppers. This is the biggest revenue-generating time of the year after all. But what if, despite your greatest efforts, you don’t see an uptick in sales by [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-boost-holiday-sales/">Last-minute tips to boost holiday sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The holiday season is upon us. You’ve decked out your homepage, planned your holiday promotions and set up a targeted communication plan to draw a maximum number of shoppers. This is the biggest revenue-generating time of the year after all. But what if, despite your greatest efforts, you don’t see an uptick in sales by early December? Don’t worry, all hope is not lost. We’ve put together a few technical tips to help you determine what might be going wrong on your site and a few marketing actions to boost sales.<br />
<span id="more-20920"></span><br />
<strong>Check on site speed.</strong> This is a busy time of year and shoppers are less patient than usual (which isn’t saying much). If your site takes more than 3 seconds to load, this could explain why you’re losing shoppers before check out. Make sure photos are optimized for the web. Get in touch with your hosting provider to let them know you’re expecting an uptick in traffic and <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/432-website-performance" target="_blank">make sure a simple technical glitch isn’t standing between you and out-of-the-park sales</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Identify problem pages.</strong> Use Google Analytics to identify 404 Error Pages that may be scaring away customers. Review your 404 Error message and make sure it’s reassuring, not cryptic and worrisome. Customers need to be assured they’re still on your site and not opening themselves up to viruses and malware.</p>
<p><strong>Verify your Adwords account.</strong> If you’re using paid advertising, double check your keywords, make sure everything is headed in the right direction. Since it’s the holidays, you might want to transfer budget to large cities that are commerce hubs, or specific customer segments. Just make sure everything is setup correctly, as a technical error could be what’s affecting your sales.</p>
<p><strong>Evaluate recent changes.</strong> If you’re not seeing traffic increase, or worse, you’re seeing a decrease during the holidays, take a minute to evaluate any changes you’ve made. You probably redid your homepage for the holidays and updated product pages. Did you overlook any important elements, like call to action buttons? Did you add complications to the sales funnel? Are your special offers and purchase triggers like free shipping clearly displayed on your site? Take time to analyze how your changes may have impacted traffic. </p>
<p><strong>Stay on top of suppliers.</strong> Ideally this is something you addressed before the holiday season got underway. If a main supplier encounters a problem that interrupts or slows production, that then becomes your problem. Try to diversify your suppliers so you’re not dependent on just one. This will keep you nimble during the holiday rush. Also, stay on top of your suppliers. Late deliveries could leave you with excess stock that could force you to take post-holiday markdowns.</p>
<p><strong>Update content.</strong> You should have holiday-themed blog posts up or ready to go. Have you embedded links back to your bestsellers in them? You should have. Review your homepage and product pages and spruce up content by adding synonyms and keywords customers are searching for. Consider creating or updating a gift guide. These simplify the shopping experience and let you put your bestsellers front and center. </p>
<p><strong>Reach out to local press.</strong> National print magazines have already moved on to planning January and February issues, but you might have a shot at getting some coverage in your local news outlets, which could give you added visibility when you need it.</p>
<p><strong>Get serious on social.</strong> Social media is a great tool to boost holiday sales. Try offering a social-media only promotion or holding a contest online. You’ll have to make your deals incredibly tempting, but if you’ve got low-performing inventory you want to move, consider bundling it into gifts or offering a giveaway with a certain purchase level.</p>
<p><strong>Have communication ready in case of unforeseen events.</strong> Some things are simply out of your control: no one expects you to stop snowstorms or strikes. However, they do expect you to troubleshoot and communicate. Have an email ready to send explaining that you’re doing your best to work around whatever incident has arisen. You’ll be able to fill in a few more details just before you send it. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-boost-holiday-sales/">Last-minute tips to boost holiday sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-boost-holiday-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data management for small ecommerce businesses</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/data-management-small-ecommerce-businesses/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/data-management-small-ecommerce-businesses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 13:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The sales process used to be fairly simple, generating data that was easy to visualize and track. But ecommerce changed all that. Today, an online purchase generates a storm of data that can be used to improve sales performance—if you know how to harness it. Large companies have understood this and invest in exploiting that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/data-management-small-ecommerce-businesses/">Data management for small ecommerce businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sales process used to be fairly simple, generating data that was easy to visualize and track. But ecommerce changed all that. Today, an online purchase generates a storm of data that can be used to improve sales performance—if you know how to harness it. Large companies have understood this and invest in exploiting that data. Small businesses can reap the benefits from this information as well, although they have to be a bit more nimble in doing so, given their limited human and financial resources. Here are a few ideas for how small businesses can go beyond simply monitoring data and turn it into a competitive advantage, especially for identifying actions during key sales periods.<br />
<span id="more-20912"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#59bbc4">Identify patterns</h2>
<p>Finding patterns in data starts with monitoring activity, but it doesn’t end there. The key to making the most of data is to look for patterns: What are your customers buying? How are they finding it? Are they coming back? How much are they spending? Can you get them to spend more, and more often? </p>
<p>It helps to think of sales and marketing processes in terms of funnels. You might send 1,000 emails for a campaign that result in 10 recipients buying something. What happens along the way and why, is crucial to helping you determine what to change in your process in order to better respond to your customers. </p>
<p>Here’s an example of a typical email campaign funnel:</p>
<ol>
<li>You send 1,000 past customers an email promoting your holiday sale.</li>
<li>Of the 1,000 sent, 980 are delivered by your email service.</li>
<li>Of the 980 delivered, 325 are opened by past customers.</li>
<li>Of the 325 opened, 40 click on a product link in the email.</li>
<li>Of the 40 that clicked, 35 add a product to their shopping cart.</li>
<li>Of the 35 that add products to their shopping cart, 8 follow through with the purchase.</li>
</ol>
<p>Having data about each “narrowing” of the funnel helps you understand where problems may be occurring and where to focus your efforts and resources. </p>
<p>To a see a real shift in business requires consolidating the data gathered from monitoring, analyzing the results over time, and testing variations on strategy to see what happens. Any time is the perfect time to start gathering and analyzing data, but the holiday season is a particularly good time because it’s such a heavy-hitting time of year and ideally you’ll want to improve your performance each year. </p>
<h2 style="color:#59bbc4">Set goals</h2>
<p>It helps to have a goal in order to determine if what you’re doing is working and if it’s even right for your business. For example, are you trying to increase traffic? Boost sales? Reduce customer service calls? In order to test and monitor for these goals, you’ll want to establish a set of key performance indicators, or KPIs, to guide your analysis. Here are a few ideas to get you started thinking about what KPIs to focus on:</p>
<p><strong>Goal:</strong> Increase Site Traffic 25%<br />
<strong>KPIs:</strong> site traffic, sources, click-through rates, social shares, bounce rates. </p>
<p><strong>Goal:</strong> Increase Sales 10%<br />
<strong>KPIs:</strong> Daily sales, conversion rate, site traffic</p>
<p><strong>Goal:</strong> Increase conversions 5%<br />
<strong>KPIs:</strong> Conversion rate, shopping cart abandonment rate, competitive price trends. </p>
<h2 style="color:#59bbc4">Test your ideas</h2>
<p>Split testing is a small business owner’s best friend. Once you’ve decided what your goal is and what KPIs you’re going to focus on, you can start getting scientific about how you’re going to get there. Start by identifying different page layouts for product pages and split testing them to see what resonates most with your customers. You can do the same thing with email campaigns and social media projects. </p>
<p>Here are a few examples of things to test on your website: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Product images</li>
<li>Product descriptions</li>
<li>Call to action button text</li>
<li>Call to action button position</li>
</ul>
<p>Google Trends is a great place to start identifying what’s relevant in your market via the volume and popularity of searches in your field. This can inform your business from a supply and demand perspective, but also give you ideas for content and specific wording to test throughout your site, email campaigns and social media actions.</p>
<h2 style="color:#59bbc4">Tools and resources</h2>
<p>You might be thinking, okay, monitoring and analyzing is great, but how do I manage all that information? Google Analytics is a great place to start. You can run your split tests through their “experiments” function to see which changes work and which don’t. The results are not always what you’d expect, which is why it’s so interesting to perform this kind of test. Having <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/63-analytics-stats-prestashop-modules" target="_blank">all your data consolidated in one place</a> is also necessary if you’re going to draw any useful conclusions. </p>
<p>You should also think about how you’re going to divide your marketing budget between customer segments. While acquisition should be an important part of your marketing budget, returning customers are actually more valuable in the long run. They are more likely to refer your brand and draw viral attention to it. You can invest in them by sending simple gifts, getting in touch with them via phone or email, or following up with special offers or coupons. By dividing your customers into segments (returning and new) you can test these initiatives and see what spurs repeat spending and increased spending. </p>
<h2 style="color:#59bbc4">Social media</h2>
<p>Social media creates a lot of data, but it can be difficult to tell what is driving conversions and what is giving you longer term visibility without necessarily resulting in immediate conversions. Facebook Insights and a platform like Hootsuite for Twitter can help you get a handle on these numbers and evaluate your activities on social media. <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/39-social-commerce-facebook-prestashop-modules" target="_blank">The PrestaShop Addons marketplace features a variety of modules</a> designed to give merchants insight into their marketing efforts, including on social media. </p>
<p>Data can be an incredible competitive advantage for small businesses that understand how to use it. Setting goals, identifying KPIs and regularly testing are the first steps to better data management. Resources like Google Trends, Google Analytics and social media tools like Hootsuite all provide free or low-cost ways to manage data, so there’s no reason to wait to start gathering and analyzing your data! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/data-management-small-ecommerce-businesses/">Data management for small ecommerce businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/data-management-small-ecommerce-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[Infographic] 17 eCommerce Conversion Boosters</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/infographic-17-ecommerce-conversion-boosters/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/infographic-17-ecommerce-conversion-boosters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that adding a video description to a product page increases its conversion by a whopping 80%, and a trust seal – by 40% more? By simply making only two improvements to your eCommerce website you could potentially raise your income by 120%. Online stores conversions depend on many factors. The most important [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/infographic-17-ecommerce-conversion-boosters/">[Infographic] 17 eCommerce Conversion Boosters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that adding a video description to a product page increases its conversion by a whopping 80%, and a trust seal – by 40% more? By simply making only two improvements to your eCommerce website you could potentially raise your income by 120%.<br />
<span id="more-20903"></span><br />
Online stores conversions depend on many factors. The most important factor in the complex approach to conversion optimization is to squeeze the most from each and every one of these factors, minimizing the losses. Why is it so important? The difference of 0.5% may seem insignificant, but depending on your overall income it may range may translate into ‘hundreds of dollars’ or ‘millions of dollars’. That’s why <strong> each hundredth of a percent counts</strong>.</p>
<p>Today’s Infographic reveals 17 key factors that influence your store’s conversion rates and the average order amount. And since you’ve launched your shop with PrestaShop, you will find some useful modules that will do a part of the work for you.</p>
<p>Even if you are an expert with years of experience in selling online, it doesn’t hurt to take a second look. And if you are new to online commerce, this checklist will help you achieve the highest conversion rates possible without the need to learn from experience and waste the money that you can otherwise invest into developing your business.</p>
<p>This Infographic has been designed by <a href="http://www.templatemonster.com/prestashop-themes.php?utm_source=blogprestashop&amp;utm_medium=infographicpost&amp;utm_campaign=prestashopguestographic" target="_blank">TemplateMonster</a> – the guys behind 1000+ PrestaShop themes and more than 4000 eCommerce designs overall. They compiled data from a dozen research projects into this easy-to-understand, visual presentation.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20917" alt="prestashop_compresse" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/11/prestashop_compresse.gif" width="600" height="5200" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #f36523">PrestaShop modules featured in the Infographic:</h2>
<h4 style="color: #26ad61">Product reviews</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/seo-prestashop-modules/6144-customer-ratings-and-reviews-pro-google-rich-snippets.html" target="_blank">Customer Ratings and Reviews Pro + Google Rich Snippets</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/17497-netreviews.html" target="_blank">Verified Reviews</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/15865-guestbook-orders-customers-reviews.html" target="_blank">Guestbook Orders Customers Reviews</a></li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #26ad61">Checkout</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/checkout-modules/356-one-page-checkout.html" target="_blank">One Page Checkout</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/checkout-modules/8503-one-page-checkout-ps-easy-fast-intuitive.html" target="_blank">One Page Checkout PS (Easy, Fast &amp; Intuitive)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/checkout-modules/18016-one-page-checkout-with-social-login-mailchimp.html" target="_blank">One Page Checkout with Social Login &amp; Mailchimp</a></li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #26ad61">Improved site search:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search-filters-prestashop-modules/11066-jolisearch-advanced-visual-search.html" target="_blank">JoliSearch : Advanced Visual Search</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search-filters-prestashop-modules/2778-advanced-search-4.html" target="_blank">Advanced Search 4</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search-filters-prestashop-modules/15373-yet-another-advanced-search.html" target="_blank">Yet Another Advanced Search</a></li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #26ad61">Live chat</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/18967-live-chat-pro-responsive.html" target="_blank">Live Chat Pro (Responsive)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/17874-responsive-live-chat.html" target="_blank">Responsive Live Chat</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/8275-chat-zopim-for-prestashop.html" target="_blank">Chat Zopim for Prestashop</a></li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #26ad61">Upselling &amp; cross-selling</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pricing-promotion-prestashop-modules/11345-push-on-cart-upselling.html" target="_blank">Push on Cart (Upselling)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/checkout-modules/2412-cross-selling-on-cart.html" target="_blank">Cross Selling on Cart</a></li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/slideshows-prestashop-modules/5275-slider-products-of-same-category.html" target="_blank">Slider &#8211; Products of Same Category</a></li>
</ul>
<p>What methods do you use to boost sales? Share your success story and help us all make eCommerce better.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/infographic-17-ecommerce-conversion-boosters/">[Infographic] 17 eCommerce Conversion Boosters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/infographic-17-ecommerce-conversion-boosters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using social media for your business: 4 mistakes to avoid</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-social-media-for-your-business-4-mistakes-to-avoid/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-social-media-for-your-business-4-mistakes-to-avoid/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20883</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2015, social media are an integral part of everyday life for almost all (96%) marketing professionals, who use them for both personal and professional purposes. As a business, it is important to choose marketing channels such as social media that will provide you with the best results and good ROI. Today, more and more [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-social-media-for-your-business-4-mistakes-to-avoid/">Using social media for your business: 4 mistakes to avoid</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2015, <a href="http://ow.ly/TCoYA" target="_blank">social media are an integral part of everyday life</a> for almost all (96%) marketing professionals, who use them for both personal and professional purposes. As a business, it is important to choose marketing channels such as social media that will provide you with the best results and good ROI.</p>
<p>Today, more and more small businesses are choosing social media over other marketing channels to help raise awareness of their brand, boost their sales and grow their professional network. Indeed, the figures for social media speak for themselves! Of the 3 billion people who use the Internet &#8211; i.e. 45% of the population &#8211; 2.1 billion have a social media account. There are 1.4 billion Facebook users and 248 million active Twitter users with 500 million tweets sent every day.*<br />
Another significant figure: the digital marketing budget of companies is expected to increase by 8% in 2015**.<br />
<span id="more-20883"></span><br />
But what about the things you <em>shouldn&#8217;t do</em>? Because make no mistake: some errors can be ruinous. Discover the 4 mistakes you absolutely must avoid when using social media for your business.</p>
<h2 style="color:#706da4">1. Not having a social media strategy</h2>
<p>Many companies start using social media without having guidelines or a strategy. Most importantly, lots of them have no idea of the stakes involved.</p>
<p>Why is this a mistake? Quite simply because every action taken on social media should correspond to a clear objective. If so, the rest of your social initiatives will be much easier to manage. If you don&#8217;t have a defined plan, these actions may not be clear or aligned with one another. The engagement of your subscribers and your ROI will be even more affected.</p>
<p>Does this seem complicated? Don&#8217;t worry! There are currently <a href="http://ow.ly/TCQ89" target="_blank">plans for creating social media strategies</a>. Think about your objectives, audit your social media sites, learn from the competition, <a href="http://ow.ly/TCQyP" target="_blank">create a content calendar</a> and lastly: test, test and test again in order to refine this strategy.</p>
<h2 style="color:#706da4">2. Buying &#8220;Likes&#8221; and subscribers</h2>
<p>On certain social media sites, you can buy &#8220;Likes&#8221; and subscribers. This technique was once widely used but is increasingly being criticized. Some brands prefer appealing to the “<a href="http://www.journaldunet.com/ebusiness/expert/57443/3-raisons-de-ne-pas-acheter-des-fans-facebook.shtml" target="_blank">social masses</a>”  but keep in mind that these fake &#8220;Likes&#8221; and phantom subscribers will have absolutely no impact on your results and will merely cause you to spend money. More importantly, the quality and interaction of your audience will decrease, your brand&#8217;s image will be tarnished and your ROI will be close to 0. If you want more interaction and subscribers, go with traditional solutions: word of mouth, competitions, contests, advertising, etc.</p>
<h2 style="color:#706da4">3. Posting too much content</h2>
<p>Posting content is a good strategy: it creates interaction in your accounts and provides your subscribers with information to which they will be receptive. However, if you post content too often, you may bore them in spite of their loyalty. You aren&#8217;t the only brand they follow and they won&#8217;t want or have time to digest this flow of information. In short, by posting too much content, you risk &#8220;spamming&#8221; your followers and therefore seeing them unsubscribe.</p>
<p>To avoid this mistake, create a <a href="http://ow.ly/TCQyP" target="_blank">content calendar</a> and stick to it. Be sure to post interesting and varied content that corresponds to the objective set for each social media site. Just the right amount of high-quality content is essential to the success of your social media strategy</p>
<h2 style="color:#706da4">4. Deleting negative comments</h2>
<p>The first reflex of beginners on social media sites is to delete injurious comments. Why leave such negative testimonials where everyone can see them? They&#8217;re sure to discredit you and directly affect your brand image. But think again: deleting them would be a big mistake! By doing so, you are showing everyone your guilt, sensitivity and lack of transparency. Consider these negative comments to be an opportunity: you can address them by satisfying an unhappy customer or solving a problem you might not even have been aware of, all while remaining in the public sphere. You will thus show everyone that you are professional and responsive. Even better: you can reply to these comments with some humor and thus turn the conversation to your advantage.</p>
<p>There are many other <a href="http://ow.ly/TCQLB" target="_blank">common strategic social media mistakes</a>, each one of which has a solution. What&#8217;s most important is that you have a strategy for your social media and know how to apply it. Of course, it&#8217;s easier to fall into traps when you&#8217;re just getting started on social media or are creating a new business and starting from scratch, but as the saying goes: &#8220;<em>don&#8217;t be afraid to make mistakes. Just don&#8217;t make the same mistake twice.</em>”</p>
<h4 style="color:#706da4">About the author and Hootsuite</h4>
<p>Clémence is a Content Marketing Specialist for Hootsuite. Passionate about web marketing and social media, she keeps up with the latest trends and offers advice and best practices for her readers and for users of Hootsuite.</p>
<p>For more information and advice relating to social media and the development of a social strategy, the <a href="http://ow.ly/TCQUz" target="_blank">Hootsuite blog</a> is full of resources. <a href="http://ow.ly/TCOZP" target="_blank">Hootsuite</a> offers software for the management of social media. Available in several languages, with 3 types of packages, it lets you manage all your social accounts from a single dashboard.</p>
<p>* Source: We Are Social 2015<br />
** Source: Veinteractive, December 2014</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-social-media-for-your-business-4-mistakes-to-avoid/">Using social media for your business: 4 mistakes to avoid</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-social-media-for-your-business-4-mistakes-to-avoid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce 101: Payments in a Tweet</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-payments-tweet/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-payments-tweet/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20849</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Picking a payment provider is one of the most important tasks for an online merchant, but it can also be one of the most difficult. We asked some of our payment solution partners to sum up the key benefit of their solution in a tweet. We hope this makes it easier to identify which solution [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-payments-tweet/">Ecommerce 101: Payments in a Tweet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Picking a payment provider is one of the most important tasks for an online merchant, but it can also be one of the most difficult. We asked some of our payment solution partners to sum up the key benefit of their solution in a tweet. We hope this makes it easier to identify which solution is right for your business.<br />
<span id="more-20849"></span></p>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-20856" alt="sagepay" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/sagepay.jpg" width="57" height="57" /> Looking to grow your eCommerce site? Accept payments online using the @SagePay_UK online payment gateway and build your business – now!<br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/3610-sagepay-direct.html" target="_blank">SagePay</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Looking%20to%20grow%20your%20eCommerce%20site%3F%20Accept%20payments%20online%20using%20the%20%40SagePay_UK%20online%20payment%20gateway%20and%20build%20your%20business%20%E2%80%93%20now!&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-20857" alt="simplify-commerce" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/simplify-commerce.png" width="57" height="57" /> We make it simple to accept payments on your @PrestaShop store. Try the @simplifycom free addon: <a href="http://ow.ly/KuzV6" target="_blank">http://ow.ly/KuzV6</a><br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/17104-simplifycommerce.html" target="_blank">Simplify Commerce</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=We%20make%20it%20simple%20to%20accept%20payments%20on%20your%20%40PrestaShop%20store.%20Try%20the%20%40simplifycom%20free%20addon&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="size-full wp-image-20852 alignleft" alt="desjardins" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/desjardins.png" width="57" height="57" /> Improve your online shopping experience by offering a turnkey payment solution. @DesjardinsGroup<br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/14656-desjardins.html" target="_blank">Desjardins</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Improve%20your%20online%20shopping%20experience%20by%20offering%20a%20turnkey%20payment%20solution.%20%40DesjardinsGroup&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="size-full wp-image-20854 alignright" alt="paymill" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/paymill.jpg" width="57" height="57" /> Reduce your shopping cart abandonment rate by 13% by offering up to 100 currencies in your checkout with PAYMILL <a href="http://bit.ly/1DwvaGd" target="_blank">http://bit.ly/1DwvaGd</a><br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/17640-pigmbhpaymill.html" target="_blank">PAYMILL</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Reduce%20your%20shopping%20cart%20abandonment%20rate%20by%2013%25%20by%20offering%20up%20to%20100%20currencies%20in%20your%20checkout%20with%20PAYMILL&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="size-full wp-image-20853 alignleft" alt="hipay" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/hipay.jpg" width="57" height="57" /> Grow your international business with adapted payment options! Start by using @Hipay for your local and international payments.<br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/1746-hipay.html" target="_blank">HiPay</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Grow%20your%20international%20business%20with%20adapted%20payment%20options!%20Start%20by%20using%20%40Hipay%20for%20your%20local%20and%20international%20payments.&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="size-full wp-image-20858 alignright" alt="sofort" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/sofort.png" width="60" height="60" /> Be smart! Reduce costs by using e-payment via SOFORT banking for your web shop! <a href="http://bit.ly/1gYSIJQ" target="_blank">http://bit.ly/1gYSIJQ</a><br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/9176-sofortbanking.html" target="_blank">SOFORT</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Be%20smart!%20Reduce%20costs%20by%20using%20e-payment%20via%20SOFORT%20banking%20for%20your%20web%20shop!&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<div style="margin: 20px 0; padding: 26px 20px; background-color: #f5f5f5;"><img class="size-full wp-image-20855 alignleft" alt="payplug" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/payplug.jpg" width="57" height="57" /> Integrate your payment solution and start accepting online payments in 1 minute with @PayPlug<br />
- <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/8795-online-payment-made-simple-payplug.html" target="_blank">PayPlug</a>     <a class="twitter-share-button" href="https://www.twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Integrate%20your%20payment%20solution%20and%20start%20accepting%20online%20payments%20in%201%20minute%20with%20%40PayPlug&amp;via=PrestaShop" data-size="large">Tweet_Button</a></div>
<hr style="margin-bottom: 20px;" align="left" width="20%" />
<p>Head to PrestaShop Addons to learn more about the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/4-payments-gateways-prestashop-modules" target="_blank">payments processors and gateways</a> available for your region. Or simply tweet your questions to our partners!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-payments-tweet/">Ecommerce 101: Payments in a Tweet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-payments-tweet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Black Friday and Cyber Monday are coming up fast</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/black-friday-cyber-monday-coming-fast/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/black-friday-cyber-monday-coming-fast/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 09:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20863</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Black Friday and Cyber Monday are coming up fast. We&#8217;ve put together a few stock management and merchandising tips to make sure you get the most out of the big weekend. Stock up Before you do anything else, stop and check your inventory! There&#8217;s nothing worse than running out of bestselling products in the middle [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/black-friday-cyber-monday-coming-fast/">Black Friday and Cyber Monday are coming up fast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Black Friday and Cyber Monday are coming up fast. We&#8217;ve put together a few stock management and merchandising tips to make sure you get the most out of the big weekend.<br />
<span id="more-20863"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Stock up</h2>
<p>Before you do anything else, stop and check your inventory! There&#8217;s nothing worse than running out of bestselling products in the middle of the holiday heyday. If you sell through marketplaces like Amazon as well, don&#8217;t underestimate how much you&#8217;re likely to sell. This is probably the one time when overstocking is not a bad thing.</p>
<p>When considering what to order and how much, ask yourself the following questions:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>What sold well last year?</li>
<li>What did you run out of?</li>
<li>What did you hope to sell more of?</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Get ready for the rush</h2>
<p>Next, think about traffic and capacity. Is your site optimized to handle the holiday rush? Is your stock management system up to date and accurate—in other words, do you know how many products you actually have?</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve stocked up and made sure your site is ready to handle the holiday rush, double check your fulfillment process to be sure you meet shipping dates and get gifts to customers on time. Post shipping dates clearly on your website so there&#8217;s no confusion.</p>
<p>Finally, don&#8217;t skimp on security. This is definitely not the time for a security breach, with the increase of customers sharing their private information as they make purchases on your site. It&#8217;s a good idea to let your payment processor know you expect increased visits.</p>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Stand out from the crowd</h2>
<p>Everyone is competing for attention at the holidays, and with good reason: the holiday season can bring in up to 30% of revenue for online merchants, in some cases up to 50%! With so many stores counting on great sales, customers are going to be facing an avalanche of promotions. Make sure you stand out from the crowd with <strong>highly-targeted, unique</strong> content.</p>
<p>Everyone will be advertising their sales and promotions in email subject titles, so consider another approach, like humor, to stand out. If that&#8217;s not your style, try crafting your titles to speak to your target segments, especially top customers. Put all the data you&#8217;ve collected over the last year to work for you to personalize emails and aggressively retarget key customer segments.</p>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Guide your customers to the perfect gift</h2>
<p>Customers will be cramming as much shopping in on Black Friday and Cyber Monday as they can. Make it easy for them to find what they need on your site by putting together gift guides that address different customer types, like moms and dads, or product categories, like stocking stuffers or winter duds.</p>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Throw in free shipping</h2>
<p>Customers love a good deal this time of the year, but they love free shipping even more. In fact, shipping fees contribute more than anything else to abandoned carts. This might seem like a big investment for small businesses, but the fact is, shipping fees could be what turn customers away from your site and to the competition.</p>
<p>To take some of the risk out of offering free shipping, ask yourself a few questions to optimize the shipping process:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>How many customers didn&#8217;t receive their order on time?</li>
<li>How did our partners perform?</li>
<li>What was the most popular shipping option?</li>
<li>Were my shipping cut-off dates accurate enough for domestic and international customers?</li>
<li>What were my fulfilment and shipping costs?</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Don&#8217;t forget your &#8220;404 Page Not Found&#8221; and &#8220;No Results Found&#8221; pages</h2>
<p>Customer searches may turn up negative for a variety reasons, from spelling errors to different regional names for the same product. Don&#8217;t lose customers by dead-ending them at an error page. Optimize these pages by suggesting similar products or displaying a page of bestsellers.</p>
<h2 style="color: #846060;">Take our Black Friday/Cyber Monday survey!</h2>
<p>Black Friday and Cyber Monday generate incredible sales in the United States, but their impact in other countries varies: do merchants practice Black Friday and Cyber Monday sales in Europe? Do South American customers expect extreme deals at this time of year? What about Asia?</p>
<p>To understand how these key dates impact PrestaShop merchants not only in the US but around the world, we&#8217;ve put together a survey and we&#8217;d love it if you&#8217;d participate! We&#8217;ll share the results in an update to this article and on social media.</p>
<p>What are you doing to prepare for Black Friday and Cyber Monday? Let us know in the comments!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/black-friday-cyber-monday-coming-fast/">Black Friday and Cyber Monday are coming up fast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/black-friday-cyber-monday-coming-fast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 merchandising musts to boost your holiday sales</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-merchandising-musts-boost-holiday-sales/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-merchandising-musts-boost-holiday-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 13:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20839</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As we settle into the nice chill that fall brings, it’s also game time for all SMB’s looking to win this holiday season. As crates of inventory start filling up your warehouse, it’s time to make your website more festive. Today we share 5 ways to spruce up your website. Update all or just a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-merchandising-musts-boost-holiday-sales/">5 merchandising musts to boost your holiday sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we settle into the nice chill that fall brings, it’s also game time for all SMB’s looking to win this holiday season. As crates of inventory start filling up your warehouse, it’s time to make your website more festive.</p>
<p>Today we share 5 ways to spruce up your website. Update all or just a couple of these areas, and you’ll be set to go!<br />
<span id="more-20839"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #95c938">1. Home page design</h2>
<p>Update your home page with festive design elements. If you’re using the default template, consider adding a few images that promote your holiday offers to the slider. If you’re really into the holiday spirit (and have extra time and resources), you can completely redesign your homepage for the holidays. From changing the color scheme of your website to implementing new holiday-specific elements to your website, let your creativity drive your design &#8212; just be sure your brand in reflected in the design.</p>
<h2 style="color: #95c938">2. Display bestsellers</h2>
<p>After you’ve added some tinsel to your shop, it’s time to improve the user experience. Start by displaying your bestsellers and your holiday favorites. Highlight them on your homepage to drive additional traffic to the products. Featured products help shoppers find exactly what they’re looking for.</p>
<p>To further improve the user experience, segment your products into easy, shoppable categories. Start with a link to all products featured in “Cyber Monday” deals. Next, create gift guides for the customers you target. Family members are a great place to start; other ideas include co-workers and Secret Santas. Finally, consider creating price buckets for customers shopping on a budget. Group similarly priced items into the same category to make shopping even easier. Make them festive with holiday themes! For more ideas on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-awesome-ideas-valentines-day-gift-guides/">gift guides, check out our Valentine’s Day ideas</a>, which can be easily adapted for the holidays.</p>
<h2 style="color: #95c938">3. Advertise special offers</h2>
<p>Once you finalize your holiday <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-tips-successful-sales-campaign/">sales campaigns</a>, it’s important to promote them to your customers.<br />
If you guarantee shipping for orders place by a specific date, be sure to highlight that as well.</p>
<p>Prime spots to display your sales on your website include the homepage, category pages, header and within the shopping cart. For more ways to promote your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/a-quick-guide-to-promoting-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-sales/">Black Friday / Cyber Monday sale</a>, check out our tips from last year.</p>
<h2 style="color: #95c938">4. Product pages</h2>
<p>Your product pages play a key role in converting shoppers. They should clearly and accurately reflect your products both visually and in text descriptions. Check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-ecommerce-guide-to-gorgeous-product-photography/">DIY photography guide</a> for more on taking great photos.</p>
<p>Next, make sure the text on your homepage helps convert customers. Include product titles that clearly describe your products. Be sure to use keywords that customers are searching for. If there are many ways to describe your products (e.g. Tee, T-Shirt, Tee Shirt), include each instance as a product tag so they can easily be indexed by your on-site search. For more examples of great product pages check out these <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-examples-of-ecommerce-product-pages-that-convert/">PrestaShop Merchants</a>.</p>
<p>Last but not least, make sure your prices are clearly listed. With so many people to shop for, customers will be shopping around for the best deals. Display your price clearly so there are no questions or confusion.</p>
<h2 style="color: #95c938">5. <a style="color: #95c38;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size: 28px;text-decoration: underline" href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?search_query=cross+selling" target="_blank">Cross selling</a> &amp; <a style="color: #95c38;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;font-size: 28px;text-decoration: underline" href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?search_query=up-sell" target="_blank">up-selling</a></h2>
<p>Once you’ve perfected your product pages, consider improving your average order value (AOV). The most common ways include cross selling and upselling your products. When you cross-sell, you offer additional products that complement your customers’ current selection: if you’re selling a hand cream, display the foot cream from the same collection. Upselling is a technique used to get customers to upgrade their selection: if you created a holiday package that includes the hand cream, convince customers to upgrade to the entire holiday package instead of purchasing an individual item.</p>
<p>Get more ideas for <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-increase-ecommerce-cart-value/">increasing your ecommerce cart value</a> with this article.</p>
<h2 style="color: #95c938">Next Steps:</h2>
<p>Once you’ve finished merchandising your shop, be sure you go back and test all the new pages and links you’ve created. Here’s a mini checklist of the audit you should perform.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Remove out of stock products, so customers aren’t disappointed.</li>
<li>Test all links in your navigation bar.</li>
<li>Make sure all your new product categories and gift guides are easily accessible from the homepage.</li>
<li>Click through several products to make sure your cross / up selling features work.</li>
<li>Complete a test order to make sure your changes didn’t introduce new bugs.</li>
<li>If you’ve <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/quick-easy-settings-speed-prestashop-store/">turned off caching</a> while you were designing your site, be sure to turn those features back on.</li>
</ul>
<p>Are you ready for the holiday season? Share your tips and advice in the comments below!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-merchandising-musts-boost-holiday-sales/">5 merchandising musts to boost your holiday sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-merchandising-musts-boost-holiday-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The beginner’s guide to sales forecasting for small businesses</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-beginners-guide-to-sales-forecasting-for-small-businesses/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-beginners-guide-to-sales-forecasting-for-small-businesses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 13:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20813</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Business Dictionary defines forecasting as a planning tool that helps management in its attempts to cope with the uncertainty of the future, relying mainly on past and present data, and trend analysis. In other words: predicting the future. For merchants, of course, this boils down to predicting sales. Many small businesses don’t think investing in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-beginners-guide-to-sales-forecasting-for-small-businesses/">The beginner’s guide to sales forecasting for small businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.businessdictionary.com/definition/forecasting.html#ixzz3maqCFo2f" target="_blank">Business Dictionary</a> defines <strong>forecasting</strong> as a planning tool that helps management in its attempts to cope with the uncertainty of the future, relying mainly on past and present data, and trend analysis. In other words: predicting the future. For merchants, of course, this boils down to predicting sales.<br />
Many small businesses don’t think investing in forecasting early on is essential, but in fact, it can be a big help in determining performance, and predicting and maintaining future growth.<br />
<span id="more-20813"></span><br />
If you’ve ever looked at last month’s revenue to gauge how much you’ll make the next month, then you’ve already started forecasting. In this blog article, we’ll walk you through the basic forecasting process and suggest resources for going further with more in-depth forecasting. How much you can forecast is ultimately determined by the amount of data you have, so if you’ve been in business for 3 years, your sales forecast will be more accurate and comprehensive than someone who has been in business for 3 months.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">No History Forecast</h2>
<p>Most businesses starting out will establish this type of forecast. This is a critical step in building a <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-create-an-online-store-10-steps-to-write-your-business-plan/">business plan</a> and an important factor that potential investors will consider. With no data, this forecast is pretty much just a guess. But you can use relevant information to make an educated guess. Research your industry and similar companies you’d like to emulate. Understanding how others in your field have performed can help you gauge how your own business will perform. Other considerations include: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Your track record (How successful were your previous ventures?) </li>
<li>Partner’s success rate (Are you bringing someone on board with a better success rate?) </li>
<li>Product Demand (Compare purchasing behavior and purchasing funnel) </li>
</ul>
<p>Your local chamber of commerce and other small business organizations can help you with your projection based on their experience with similar companies. The more research you have, the more accurate your predictions will be. </p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">1 Month History Forecast</h2>
<p>Once you’ve made your first month’s sales, it’s easy to guess what the next month will look like.  Barring any major fluke events, this method will give you a ballpark sales figure. Unfortunately, it’s not always a very reliable method. An obvious example is the holiday season: if you make $1500 in sales during the holiday season, you can’t reasonably expect to maintain the same level of sales in the months after; the holidays are an unusual event in the ecommerce sales year that tend to show increased sales. So remember, this forecast can give you a general idea of sales, but you’ll need to take context into account.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">3-Month History Forecast</h2>
<p>Collecting data for several months will give you a more accurate forecast by allowing you to average your sales across this period. You’ll also have enough data to start seeing trends. Here’s a short video on creating a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TFxm-1smXjM" target="_blank">trendline in Excel</a>. Whether you have been experiencing an increase or decrease in sales, it helps to plot your sales on a graph to really “see” where they’re going.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">1-Year History Forecast</h2>
<p>If you continue to plot your sales throughout the year, you’ll start to see a clearer sales trajectory. However, you might also notice clear rises and drops in sales across different seasons. This is mostly due to high sales seasons around the holidays and the lack of sales during slow seasons like summer. In forecasting, this is called seasonality. To forecast next quarter’s sales, calculate the annual average and sales averages for each of the quarters. Now divide each quarter’s sales by the average.  Next, estimate the amount you expect to make the following year. Take that prediction and multiply it by the effect seasonality plays on your business. The result is the estimated quarterly sales.</p>
<p>See below for an example using 11.8% annual growth. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/tab-guide-en.png" alt="tab-guide-en" width="479" height="233" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20815" /></p>
<p>For another approach, check out this <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/billconerly/2014/12/17/how-to-adjust-your-business-data-for-seasonality/" target="_blank">Forbes’</a> how to article.</p>
<h2>Multi-year History Forecasting</h2>
<p>Once you collect data across multiple years, you’ll see that you no longer have to estimate the following year’s growth. You’ll be able to solve for that using previous years’ numbers, essentially removing almost the guesswork in your forecast. Once you accumulate that data, we recommend creating an excel spreadsheet with all your sales information. Then use built in functions to create a table that will automatically provide sales information. We suggest reading this article on <a href="http://www.exceluser.com/excel_dashboards/seasonality-sales.htm" target="_blank">creating a rolling forecast of seasonal sales in Excel</a>. Again, it will require that you have extensive data to feed into the spreadsheet. Once you do, you’ll have a pretty accurate projection for next month’s sales.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Why Small Businesses Should Forecast</h2>
<p>If you’re just starting out, forecasting sales is a critical step in putting together your business plan. Once you’ve been in business for some time, it’s forecasting is useful to predict sales. However, forecasting can be great tool for many other business functions: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Forecasting expenses</li>
<li>Inventory reordering </li>
<li>Product performance (new products)</li>
<li>Evaluate new marketing efforts </li>
<li>Revenue forecast (Sales &#8211; expenses)</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Flawed Forecasts</h2>
<p>Keep in mind that with any predictions, there are some underlying assumptions you may take for granted. Forecasts do not account for extenuating circumstances like natural disasters or any crashes in the overall market or even your industry. Keep in mind that forecasts provide numbers; it’s up to you to interpret the information correctly. </p>
<p>Start forecasting your holidays sales today. Then surpass your sales projections by checking out these <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7_ways_to_boost_your_christmas_sales/">7 ways to boost Christmas Sales</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-beginners-guide-to-sales-forecasting-for-small-businesses/">The beginner’s guide to sales forecasting for small businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-beginners-guide-to-sales-forecasting-for-small-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shipping deadlines for packages</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/shipping-deadlines-packages/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/shipping-deadlines-packages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 13:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20827</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The holiday season brings with it some of the year’s most pleasant opportunities for celebration: snow days, if you’re lucky, and time off to spend with friends and family. This is also the time most businesses make most of their sales. From trinkets to lavish gifts, shoppers are in the mood to buy gifts. Online [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/shipping-deadlines-packages/">Shipping deadlines for packages</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The holiday season brings with it some of the year’s most pleasant opportunities for celebration: snow days, if you’re lucky, and time off to spend with friends and family. This is also the time most businesses make most of their sales. From trinkets to lavish gifts, shoppers are in the mood to buy gifts. Online retailers face the annual challenge of delivering goods in time for the holidays. As part of our 2015 holiday guide, we’re helping you succeed this season with shipping deadlines from 3 of the top US carriers.<br />
<span id="more-20827"></span><br />
The mad dash for holiday gifts generally happens during and after Black Friday. With so many great deals, it’s hard to pass up the opportunity to save.  If you’re guaranteeing delivery by the holidays&#8211; Christmas to be exact&#8211;it’s important to note the shipping cutoff dates. Packages shipped after these dates will unfortunately&#8211;and to the disappointment of your customers&#8211;arrive after the holidays. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/calendar.png" alt="calendar" width="625" height="428" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20831" /></p>
<p>When you’re marketing your sales and delivery guarantees, be sure to consider the amount of time it will take for you to process the increased number of orders. Consider enlisting additional help or simply factor in more processing time.</p>
<h2 style="color:#c33d3a">Shipping Speeds and Deadlines</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/shipping-speed-deadlines.png" alt="shipping-speed-deadlines" width="464" height="433" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20829" /></p>
<p><em>*Trademarks: All trademarks and registered trademarks are the property of their respective owners.</em></p>
<h2 style="color:#c33d3a">Delays</h2>
<p>Regardless of which shipping provider you select, there’s <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2013-12-27/ups-shipping-delays-show-perils-of-stores-overpromising" target="_blank">always a chance your package</a> will be delayed. From snowstorms to misplaced packages, it’s unavoidable and can happen to anyone. Take matters into your own hands by shipping as early as you can. This way you’ll still have time to expedite another package to your customer should any unforeseen problems arise. </p>
<p>If you really can’t get your products shipped early you’ll be relying on your carrier’s promise to delivery the packages on time. In the event your package isn’t delivered on time, you can file a claim to get a refund on your shiping. To automate this process, consider adding <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules/19096-71lbs-fedex-ups-shipping-refunds.html" target="_blank">71 lbs’ shipping refunds module</a> to your shop &#8211; it’s free to install and you will only be billed for 50% of the claims they win. </p>
<h2 style="color:#c33d3a">International Packages</h2>
<p>Ship early. The only thing certain about international shipping is that nothing is certain! Each country has a own unique process, be it for deliveries to US embassies and military bases or residences. Every international package must pass customs, regardless of who is moving it. Missing paperwork, outstanding taxes and fees, flags for full inspections or even misplaced packages can cause delays even your shipping carrier can’t anticipate. </p>
<p>After the package has successfully passed customs, it is either passed to a local shipping carrier or the local offices of your domestic carrier. If it gets passed along to a local carrier, keep in mind that you may not receive additional tracking information. </p>
<h2 style="color:#c33d3a">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Planning your shipping strategy plays a key role in your holiday success. Keep customers happy by giving them plenty of time to shop for gifts and receive them in time for the holidays. For a detailed description of each carrier’s shipping schedule, please refer to their holiday schedules listed below: </p>
<p>USPS: <a href="https://www.usps.com/holiday/holiday-shipping-dates.htm" target="_blank">https://www.usps.com/holiday/holiday-shipping-dates.htm</a><br />
UPS: <a href="http://compass.ups.com/ups-holiday-calendar/" target="_blank">http://compass.ups.com/ups-holiday-calendar/</a><br />
FedEx: <a href="http://www.fedex.com/us/holiday/last-days-to-ship.html" target="_blank">http://www.fedex.com/us/holiday/last-days-to-ship.html</a></p>
<p>For additional tips and advice on maximizing your shop’s sales, operations and more this holiday season, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-holiday-guide">download our free 2015 Holiday Guide</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/shipping-deadlines-packages/">Shipping deadlines for packages</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/shipping-deadlines-packages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
